### **Tomas Madariaga**

1311 Bonita Ave 94709 Berkeley CA, +1 510 338 2169 madariaga.tomas@gmail.com

#### **PROFILE**

www.tomasmadariaga.com - es.linkedin.com/in/tomasmadariaga/en - www.github.com/tomasmax

Full stack Software Engineer, Product Manager, IT consultant with 4+ years working experience in several Start-ups and in a Big B2B consulting company with a multi-cultural background (Europe & USA). Computer Science & Industrial Engineering. Agile Project Management MSc. Big Thinker, Lifelong Learner, Entrepreneur, Business & Result oriented. Ability to learn new programming languages, frameworks and technologies quickly. Willing to create new prototypes, products & solutions. Fluent in English, native Spanish and Basque, medium in French.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Full Stack Engineer & Product Manager. San Francisco, Moovit

August 2016 - Present

- Work hand in hand with product, engineering and business development team to overhaul <a href="www.moovitapp.com">www.moovitapp.com</a> 5.0
  version release for #1 transit App Worldwide present in 67 Countries, 1200 Cities, with 45+ Million users and \$80 Millions of Investment.
- Front End development (HTML5, JavaScript, Angular2, AWS) for wining SEO, working closely to the UX/UI teams and bring wireframes & design to life.
- Android development. Data mine Moovit user's information and develop data visualization products.
- Serve as product manager to translate new features into technical requirements. App & Web prototyping.

#### Mobile & GIS Full Stack Engineer and Consultant. Spain, Indra

January 2015 - July 2016

- Consultancy and development of a Windows tablet & Android <a href="mailto:several utility companies">several utility companies</a> network. ESRI GIS back end with JBOSS server. It currently supports the management of more than one million supply points for EDP, over 9,600 kilometers of distribution network, half a million network elements and 90 maintenance teams.
- Android, Java, .NET Desk & Web development and B2B Mobile & GIS consulting.

#### Freelance Project Management Coach. Bilbao, Fondo Formacion Euskadi

May - July 2015

• Created a MOOC to increase France & Spain Coworking Space Managers Project Management efficiency, <u>PIRECOW</u> project.

Software Engineer & Project Manager, RoR, HTML5, Phonegap. Bilbao, Grupo Urbegi, February 2013 - December 2014

- Managed & developed <u>Council of Bizkaia's loan requests</u> filtering web service, allowing to reduce their response time Ruby on Rails, HTML5, JS and AWS.
- Development of a Crowdfunding platform. Ruby on Rails, HTML5, JS, PayPal, Stripe and AWS.
- Mediapost Group rebranding consultancy, websites design, development & SEO.
- Web Full Stack dev, RoR, HTML5, JS, AngularJS and Heroku & AWS web deployment and server maintenance.

#### Freelance Web Developer & Designer & Marketing

September – December 2013

- Connect a financial social online game with Facebook.
- Designed advertisements and marketing strategies to introduce a new IT product in the Spanish market.

#### Software Engineer Intern - Ruby on Rails, Java. Bilbao, Techabout

October 2011 - July 2012

• Meetabout entrepreneurial project Front & Back end development in Ruby on Rails, Java OSGi, HTML5, JS, jQuery.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Advanced Project Management Postgraduate Degree, University of Barcelona, Spain PMBOK, PMP, Prince2, Lean Project Management, Six Sigma. Agile methodologies: Agile, Scrum, Kanban MSE in Computer Science, GPA: 3.5, University of Deusto, Bilbao, Spain MSE in Business Engineering, (Erasmus), Solvay Brussels School, Brussels, Belgium 2012 – 2013 MSE in Industrial Engineering (Business Management), GPA: 3.5, University of Deusto 2010 – 2013 BSc in Computer Science, GPA: 3.2 University of Deusto, Bilbao, Spain 2007 – 2010

## COMPLEMENTARY EDUCATION

Machine Learning Specialization, University of Washington, Coursera

2016

<u>Big Data Specialization</u>, University of San Diego, Coursera

2016

Agile PM Foundation Certification, APMG International

2015

Programming Mobile Services for Android Handheld Systems: Concurrency by Vanderbilt University on Coursera

	Bizkaia Talentia Program, Selected because of my skills and academic record.	2013
	Software Engineering for Software as a Service, University of California, Berkeley, Coursera	2012
	Ingenio: Innovation, Creativity and Entrepreneurship Program, University of Deusto, Bilbao	2011
TECHNICAL SKILLS	Java, C/C++, Ruby on Rails, Node.js, HTML5, JavaScript, jQuery, AngularJS, EmberJS, Bootstrap, SASS, LESS, CSS3, SEO. Android and Cordova (Phonegap). MVC architecture. Professional experience in Back-end, Front-end, AWS and Heroku Proficient with GIT and SVN. TDD. SQL, SQLite, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, AWS DB. AWS Big Data, Tableau, Pental and Rapidminer.	
ADDITIONAL	Coursera's Global Translator Community (GTC) Volunteer, translate subtitles for course lecture videos.	
<b>EXPERIENCE &amp;</b>	University of Deusto Business IX Forum Employment and Entrepreneurship Business Simulator <u>winner</u> .	2013
AWARDS	<u>Ironhack program</u> Ambassador at the University of Deusto, helping founders to publicize it in Bilbao.	2014